Life is the ultimate work of art.
Vicky Cristina Barcelona is a drama, romance film directed by Woody Allen.
Two girlfriends on a summer holiday in Spain become enamored with the same painter, unaware that his
ex-wife, with whom he has a tempestuous relationship, is about to re-enter the picture.
Cristina, played by Scarlett Johansson.
Vicky, played by Rebecca Hall.
Juan Antonio Gonzalo, played by Javier Bardem.
María Elena, played by Penélope Cruz.
Narrator (voice), played by Christopher Evan Welch.
Doug, played by Chris Messina.
Vicky Cristina Barcelona is a 2008 romantic comedy drama
film written and directed by Woody Allen.
The film stars Javier Bardem, Penélope Cruz, Rebecca
Hall and Scarlett Johansson in lead roles.
The plot centers on two American women, Vicky and Cristina, who spend a summer in Barcelona, where they meet an artist, Juan Antonio,
who is attracted to both of them, while still enamored of his mentally and emotionally unstable ex-wife María Elena.
The film was shot in Spain in Barcelona, Avilés, and Oviedo, and was
Allen's fourth consecutive film shot outside the United States.
Vicky Cristina Barcelona premiered at the 2008 Cannes Film Festival on May 17, 2008, and then received a rolling worldwide
general release that started on August 15, 2008, in the United States, and September 19, 2008, in Spain.
The film emerged as a commercial success at the box office, becoming one of Allen's
highest-grossing films by grossing $96 million against a $15 million budget.
It received widespread critical acclaim upon release, with
particular praise directed towards Cruz's performance.
Cruz won the Academy Award, BAFTA Award and Independent Spirit Award for Best Supporting Actress, in
addition to SAG, Golden Globe and Critics Choice nominations in the same category.
At the 66th Golden Globe Awards, Vicky Cristina Barcelona received 4 nominations, including Best Actor in a Motion Picture – Musical or Comedy (Bardem), Best Actress
in a Motion Picture – Musical or Comedy (Hall) and Best Supporting Actress – Motion Picture (Cruz), winning Best Motion Picture – Musical or Comedy.
The film explores themes of barcelona, spain,
photographer, artist, menage a trois, painter.
The tone is emotional.